Sub queries can be especially helpful in improving the performance of your queries.
子查询特别有助于优化查询性能
Imagine you're doing some high level reporting for Parch and Posey.
想象你正在为 Parch 和 Posey 编制高级报告
You'd like to see a bunch of metrics rolled up on a daily basis.
你会看到按日积累的很多统计数据
You could use this to power a dashboard that would help run
你可以利用该功能支持创建面板 该面板将
the business day to day by quickly identifying anomalies.
快速识别异常情况 有助于公司进行日常经营
To do this, you'll need to join data from a few tables and then aggregate by day.
为此 你需要合并不同表格的数据 然后按日聚合
You could do all of this in one main query,
你可以利用一个主查询完成所有工作
but there are some big advantages to aggregating the tables individually in sub queries,
但是 通过子查询先聚合各表格
then joining the pre-aggregated sub queries.
然后合并各子查询 有一些优势
First, let's look at how we would do this with one big query.
首先 我们看一看如何用主查询来做这一工作
One thing you can see here is that to do this properly,
这里 你要明白一点 要妥当地做上述工作
we have to join date fields which causes what you might call a data explosion.
我们需要合并日期字段 这会导致你可能称之为数据爆炸的后果
Basically, what happens is that you're joining every row in a given day from
后果基本是 你把一张表格内某一给定日期的每一列
one table onto every row with the same day in the other table.
合并到另一张表格内具有相同日期的每一列
So the number of rows returned is incredibly great.
因此 返回的列数将变得难以置信地大
Because of this multiplicative effect,
由于这一倍增效应
you need to use count distinct instead of
你需要使用 count distinct 而不是
regular counts to get accurate counts of the sales rep,
普通的 count 统计销售代表的准确计数数据、
the orders, and ultimately, the web visits.
订单以及最终统计网络访问
Just take a look at how big this data set gets before aggregating.
来看看聚合前这一数据集变得多大吧
You can see that executing the join this way returned
你可以看到 这样执行合并返回
79,000 rows which then needed to be aggregated.
79,000 列 需要之后进行聚合
You can get the same result set much more
先对表格进行分别聚合 计数
efficiently by aggregating the tables separately so that
就会在小得多的数据集上执行
the counts are performed across far smaller data sets.
这样 你获得同样的结果集会高效得多
Here, we have written the first sub query.
这里 我们已经编写了第一个子查询
And here's the second sub query.
这里是第二个子查询
As you can see, both of these sub queries are around 1000 rows.
我们可以看到 这两个子查询各有大约 1000 列
This way, when we write our join,
这样 当我们编写合并语句时
we'll be joining 1000 onto 1000 rows and
我们可以把 1000 列合并到另 1000 列
joining dates onto other dates that match so it would be much less expensive.
然后合并互相匹配的日期 这会极大地降低成本
We're using a full join here just in case
这里 我们用了 full join 考虑到
one table has observations in a month that the other table doesn't.
一张表格内有某月的观察数据 而另一张表格没有
As we saw, both sub queries resolved to just about a 1000 rows,
我们能够看到 两个子查询被分解为大约只有 1000 列
and the final query ends up at just about a 1000 rows as well.
而最终查询结果也将只有大约 1000 列
So this is a whole lot better than the 79,000 rows that we
所以 比起我们之前看到的不用子查询进行预先聚合得到的 79,000 列
saw earlier when we were joining without pre-aggregating in sub queries.
这一方法要好上很多